So now that the chart is
correct, and I'm satisfied that
the information is accurate.
There may be an option that I want
to move the chart or make it bigger.
A chart works very similar to an image
within Word or PowerPoint where you can
click and hold it and move it around.
So you can move around the
screen anywhere you want.
You can resize the chart by
clicking on the small icons along
the side and in the corners.
So I can just click on that corner one
there and that will resize the chart.
It may also be a case that we need to
move the chart to another worksheet.
Now, in this instance, you would need to
click on the chart and select move chart.
The good point to note here is if you
just clicked anywhere within the chart
so, as you can see this second box in
the middle here, that is the actual data.
So if you clicked in there all you
will get is the option to change chart
types, save template, select data.
If I click in this outer area
here and right-click, I'm
given a wider range of options.
And what I want to do here
is I want to move the chart.
So if I select move chart, the
move chart, dialogue box comes up.
Now, at the moment I can move it as
an object in so I can move it into
the income or the average sales.
So I click on those income, average sales.
I can move it into one
of those worksheets.
Alternatively I can create a new
sheet and it will be called chart one.
And that will then create a new worksheet
and it will only contain the chart.
The problem with that is that I could
not create a hyperlink to that page.
So if I wanted to create a hyperlink
on the sales data worksheet that link
me directly to the chart I could not
do that on a new page, on a new sheet.
So what I would want to do is I
want to create a new worksheet.
So I'm just going to cancel out of that.
And I'm going to click plus there,
and that brings up sheet four, and I'm
going to call that sheet chart one.
So I'll just delete that.
Call it chart one.
And then if I go back to the sales
data, if I now right click, I can
move the chart and I want to move
it as an object in chart one.
So if I select that and select OK.
As you can see, it's magically
appeared on  chart one.
It's no longer in the sales data
worksheet and is now on its own worksheet.
It may be a case that I wish
to change the type of chart.
So to do that, all I can do is
on the chart design tab, as long
as I've got the chart selected,
I'll be on the chart design tab
so I could change the chart type.
So if I just have a look at that,
we could change it to a line chart.
And it gives you an example
of what it will look like.
We can change it to a pie chart.
So again, a bar chart, an area chart,
so there are a variety of different
chart types you can change it to.
So just to give an example,
I'll select pie and select OK.
And again, I don't think that gives a very
good graphical representation of the data.
I think the column chart was best, but
you can, again, on the styles, you can
change the different styles of the chart.
So you can have exploded charts as
a variety of different types there,
but I'm just going to go back to
the chart type, which was column.
And I'm just going to stick with
that one, that one will do for now.
Click OK.
And that is the column
chart on a new worksheet.
So again, the thing to remember
is that this is actually linked.
So, as you can see here, as same as you
had with the income on the average sales,
this data is linked so if I went under
the sales data and the January sales,
for some reason jumped to 880, or sorry
1,880 and I then went to the chart.
It will automatically update
the information on the chart.
So I'll just undo that.
And again, if I wanted to link
to the chart, I would just simply
click in a box and type some
text and I'll just put chart one.
And then if I right click and
select link and I select chart one,
click OK, and I'll have a hyperlink
directly to the chart one worksheet.